# Khader Taleb

Backend Developer

- (+963) 996-275-091
- khdertaleb1@gmail.com
- in linkedin.com/in/kheder-taleb
- github.com/khederTa

#### **PROFILE**

I'm a software engineer who specialists in Backend development, i work on databases, scripting languages, and website design to create the logic upon which websites and web apps function. Tasks backend developers tackle include cloud computing and API integration, security configurations, content management system deployment and maintenance and web server technologies. proficient in languages(like python and JavaScript), Django and Node.js, I have knowledge in accessibility and security compliance, and have strong organizational and communication skills.

#### **EDUCATION**

2017-2022

Information Technology/ Beachlor Degree

Al Baath University • Homs

#### **EXPERIENCE**

#### 2020 - 2021

## Expora

Remotely

#### **Backend Developer**

- Wrote quality codes to program complete applications.
- Designed, developed and implemented software applications for website based on analyzed requirements and understanding ofindustry technical standards.
- Collaborated with IT team and other support staff to develop new applications.
- Gathered user feedback and made recommendations.
- Developed and implemented scanning components using mysql, postgressql, mongodb, etc.
- Testing prorams and databases to identify issues and make necessary modifications.

## 2021 - Present

## Freelancing

Remotely

## Web Developer

- Coded websites using HTML, CSS, JAVASCRIPT, and JQUERT.
- Planned website development, converting mockups into usable web presence with HTML, JAVASCRIPT, AJAX and JSON coding.
- Modified existing code written in programming language such as JAVASCRIPT and PYTHON.
- Multi-tasked across multiple functions and roles to generate project results and meet deadlines and organizational expectation.

## SKILLS

- Creativity
- Responsibility
- Comunication
- Time Management
- Teamwork

### LANGUAGES

**Arabic -** Native

English - Very Good

## **TECHNOLOGIES**

JavaScript	HTML, CSS	
NODE.js	Django	
Python	Oracle Database	
TensorFlow	MongoDB	